outmatch.com 2019-07-25

# Privacy Policy - OutMatch

Last Updated:  5/8/2019

This Privacy Policy applies to the OutMatch.com website and all related websites, applications, services, and solutions owned and operated by OutMatch, Inc. (“ **OutMatch** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, or “ **our** ”).  OutMatch provides Talent Selection and Employee Development technology and services to our direct customers, and to our distributors and resellers (collectively, “ **Customers** ”) to improve the quality and impact of the workforce.  This policy describes how OutMatch collects and uses personal information from the following types of end users interacting with our sites:

“ **Visitors** ” – which are any end users accessing the OutMatch.com corporate web site or related OutMatch sites offering information about OutMatch, its products, and/or services. It also includes contacts in the OutMatch Customer database who are or who previously have been involved in the purchase, implementation, or administration of OutMatch solutions.

“ **Platform Users** ” – which are end users accessing our SaaS platform as part of our delivery of OutMatch products and services to our Customers.  Platform Users can include but are not limited to job applicants, references, and Customer employees participating in or managing recruiting, development, or performance measurement processes for our Customers.

As an individual accessing OutMatch site(s), you fall into one or both of the user types above, depending on your activities on the site(s).  If you need assistance determining your role as it applies to this Privacy Policy, please contact [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:support@outmatch.com).

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.  If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our sites.  By accessing or using this Website, you agree to this Privacy Policy.  This policy may change from time to time (see “7. Privacy Policy Changes”).  Your continued use of this Website after we make changes is deemed acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

This policy describes the purpose for collection, what information we collect under various circumstances, how it is collected, when it is shared, transferred, or disclosed, how it is secured, and your options for accessing, changing, removing, or limiting the use and disclosure of your personal information.

1\. Privacy Shield

OutMatch, Inc., including our U.S. subsidiaries Pomello, Chequed.com, HIREQ MERGER SUB, LLC, and The Devine Group, complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield.  OutMatch has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

OutMatch is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  OutMatch complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, OutMatch is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, OutMatch may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, OutMatch commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact OutMatch at [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:privacy@outmatch.com).

OutMatch commits to cooperate with the panel established by the EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner, as applicable and comply with the advice given by the panel and/or Commissioner, as applicable with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and/or Switzerland, as applicable in the context of the employment relationship.

OutMatch has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, you may visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information or to file a complaint (free of charge).

Under certain conditions, Privacy Shield provides the right to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have not provided resolution. This is described in [Annex I to the Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction).

2\. Purpose for Collection, Limitations, and Retention

The purpose for collecting personal information differs for Visitors and Platform Users.

_Visitors._   OutMatch collects information from Visitors to market OutMatch technology and services to OutMatch’s Visitors.

_Platform Users._   OutMatch, as a Data Processor, collects, maintains, and processes information from Platform Users on behalf of our Customers (Data Controllers), according to their instructions, to deliver our technology and services to our Customers, and to improve and develop new technology and services.

_Visitors and Platform Users._   For both Visitors and Platform Users, we may also use collected information to operate the site(s), provide technical troubleshooting or support, solicit feedback, and provide notice and alerts of product upgrades, planned maintenance, or downtime.  We may use personal information you previously provided while visiting our website when you return on subsequent visits, for your convenience and in order to help you avoid providing the same information repeatedly.  For Platform Users, this includes potentially re-using information related to a prior recruiting, development, or performance management process for a new process (for example, the ability to re-use assessment answers for multiple job applications for the same Customer).

The use of personal information shall be limited to the purpose for collection described above.  OutMatch may retain personal information indefinitely unless otherwise requested to remove it by a Visitor, Platform User, or Customer.  For information on how to make a request to access, correct, amend, delete, limit use, or limit disclosure of your information, see Section 6 (Personal Information Access and Choices).  OutMatch will retain and use the information as needed to comply with legal requirements, dispute resolution, and enforce our agreements with Customers and third parties.

3\. Collection of Information

OutMatch collects information from Visitors and Platform Users who choose to provide it explicitly.  We may also receive information necessary to deliver OutMatch technology and services to our Customers from third-party sources operated by or contracted by our Customers (“Customer Systems”).  We also collect information automatically using commonly used logging and tracking technologies (see Logging and Tracking below).  The information we collect may vary by user type according to the method and purpose for collection.

3.1.   Explicit Collection

_Visitors_.  We collect information that you voluntarily provide, such as name, email, address, phone number, company, and job title so that we may contact you for the purposes described above.  When purchasing products and/or services, OutMatch may also require you to provide financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, and credit card number (“Billing Information”).

_Platform Users_.  We collect information related to and necessary for delivering our employee selection, development, and performance measurement services to our Customers.  This information will vary based on your role in those processes, but may include (but not be limited to) items such as name, email, address, demographic information, job application information, reference or feedback information, interview information, job performance information, and responses to questions associated with our core products and services.

3.2.   Inbound from Customer Systems

_Visitors_.  No information is collected in this manner.

_Platform Users_.  We collect information related to and necessary for delivering our employee selection, development, and performance measurement services to our Customers.  This information will vary based on your role in those processes, but may include (but not be limited to) items such as name, email, address, demographic information, job application information, reference or feedback information, interview information, job performance information, and responses to questions associated with our core products and services.  In some cases, OutMatch has no control over the type of information transferred inbound from Customer Systems, and while it may not be stored and used for OutMatch purposes, it may be retained in logs captured during automated communications with Customer Systems.

3.3.   Logging and Tracking

OutMatch and its marketing partners, affiliates, analytics or service providers may use cookies, beacons, tags, scripts, locally stored objects, and log files to analyze trends, administer the sites, track user movements around the sites and to gather Visitor demographic information.  We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies from those parties on an individual or aggregated basis.  The information collected from these technologies may be linked to other Visitor or Platform User information.

3.3.1.  Cookies and other browser-based storage; web beacons

These technologies may be used to access the site(s) and use their features, or to improve and optimize the experience on our sites (for example to recognize a returning Visitor or Platform User, or to know and track if users are currently logged into our sites), or to provide you with more relevant messages, including marketing communications (see Advertising below).  Users control the use of these technologies using various management techniques available in their web browser.  Depending on the OutMatch site visited, disabling technologies such as cookies could completely prevent users from accessing the site(s), or simply limit the use of certain features or functions.

OutMatch may use web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Visitors’ usage of the site(s) and interaction with emails from OutMatch.

3.3.2.  Logs

Similar to most websites, OutMatch automatically collects certain information and stores it in logs.  This consists of commonly logged user-to-server information such as device internet protocol (IP) address, device type, browser and operating system type, pages accessed and parameters passed during access, information submitted during access, date and time, and referring and exit pages.

3.3.3.  Advertising

_Visitors_.  We partner with third parties to either display advertising on our sites or control our advertising on other non-OutMatch sites.  These partners may use the technologies in Section 3.3.1 above to gather Visitor information or activities on the OutMatch site(s), emails, and third-party sites, in order to provide advertising based on Visitor browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for serving you interest-based advertising, you should clear cookies and other site data from your browser cache, and avoid accessing the site(s).

We may also receive information about Visitors from other sources, including third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this information with data we already have.  This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and create more tailored advertising to provide products and services that may be of interest to you.

_Platform Users_.  The OutMatch platform and site(s) delivering technology and services to our Customers do not make us of technologies for the purpose of advertising.

4\. Sharing and Disclosure of Information

OutMatch will only share information with third parties in the ways we describe in this policy.  OutMatch will obtain your consent prior to any other type of disclosure or transfer not listed in this policy.

4.1.   Transfers to OutMatch third parties

OutMatch partners with and occasionally hires other companies to provide services on its behalf.  Visitor or Platform User personal information may be shared with these companies; however, the use of such information is limited to the applicable purpose for collection (see Section 2).  These companies are required to maintain the confidentiality and security of personal information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

4.2.   Transfers to Customers and Customer Systems

Platform User information is collected for the purpose described in Section 2 related to the delivery of OutMatch technology and services to our Customers.  To fulfill our Customer agreements, OutMatch may transfer applicable Platform User information directly to Customers or to Customer Systems as part of an integration with those systems.  Only Platform User information directly affiliated and linked to a particular Customer may be transferred to that Customer or Customer System.  Once transferred to Customers and Customer Systems, your information is governed by their respective privacy policies.

4.3.   Transfers to Business Partners

_Visitors_.  OutMatch may partner with other companies to jointly offer products, services, or content.  If you as a Visitor purchase, specifically express interest in, register for, or download a jointly–offered product, service, or content from or through OutMatch, we may share Visitor information collected in connection with your purchase or expression of interest with our partner(s). Once transferred to Business Partners, your information is governed by their respective privacy policies.

_Platform Users_.  Platform User information would only be transferred to Business Partners as part of fulfilling a contractual agreement with our Customers consistent with their instructions and the purposes outlined in Section 2.

4.4.   Billing

OutMatch uses a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on the OutMatch’s behalf.

4.5.   No selling

OutMatch will not sell any Visitor or Platform User personal information to third parties.

4.6.   Limitations of ad targeting

Visitor information is used for ad targeting as described in Section 3.  We will not use any Platform User information for ad targeting.

4.7.   Anonymous aggregated information

OutMatch may aggregate and anonymize (remove identifiable information) personal information of Visitors and Platform Users for marketing, research, or any other lawful purpose, and may publish information in this anonymous format.

4.8.   Other disclosures

OutMatch may disclose your information when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect your safety or the safety of others; to investigate fraud or respond to a government, judicial, or other legal request; and to comply with the law.  If OutMatch is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets that involves Visitor and/or Platform User information, prominent notice will be placed on the OutMatch web site, and personal information may be transferred to involved parties.

4.9.   Jurisdiction

With respect to personal data received or transferred, OutMatch is subject to the regulatory investigation and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

5\. Securing Personal Information

The security of your information is important to OutMatch.  We protect personal information using industry-standard, commercially reasonable physical and technical mechanisms, as well as operational and administrative practices to secure all information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure.  Data is stored in data centers with physical access controls, monitored by security personnel, and restricted to authorized personnel only.  All data is encrypted using industry standard protocols as it travels over the internet (for example from your computer or phone to our servers).

Of course, no method of transmission or storage is completely secure, therefore we cannot guarantee its absolute security.  If you have questions about security practices on our site(s) or of our platform or services, please contact us at [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:privacy@outmatch.com).

6\. Personal Information Access and Choices

6.1.   Requests for Access and Changes

Upon request, OutMatch will provide you with information about whether we hold or process any of your personal information, the type of information we hold, and if it is held on behalf of OutMatch or on behalf of one or more Customers as part of Customer services agreements.  Please contact us at [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:privacy@outmatch.com) for such a request, and for assistance with any request to access, correct, amend, delete, limit use, or limit disclosure of your information.

If we hold Platform User information as part of a Customer services agreement(s), we may be required to refer you to the OutMatch Customer(s) (the data controller) to process any request to access, correct, amend, delete, limit use, or limit disclosure of your information.  Based on regional data privacy laws and regulations, and/or Customer human resources policies or other corporate restrictions, our ability to directly process your request may be limited.  If we refer your request to a Customer, OutMatch will support that Customer in responding to your request.

In certain circumstances, we may be required by law to retain your personal information.

6.2.   Marketing Opt-Out Preferences

_Visitors_.  You may receive ongoing marketing email communications if you have previously submitted personal information as part of a visit to our site(s).  You may choose to opt-out of receiving future marketing communications by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, or by contacting us at [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:privacy@outmatch.com).

_Platform Users_.  Platform Users will not receive marketing email communications.

7\. Privacy Policy Changes

We may update this policy at any time by posting a revised version on OutMatch site(s).  The revised version will be effective at the time of its posting.  We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

8\. Contacting OutMatch about Privacy

If you have questions, comments, or concerns about your privacy or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@outmatch.com](mailto:privacy@outmatch.com).
